(upbeat music)
- Hi, everybody and welcome to another episode
of Little Fish.
My name's Andrew Hunter-Marry.
I'm here with James Harkin and Anna Tajinsky
and we are here to read out the best of your facts
that you've been sending into the fish inbox
over the last seven days.
Hi guys.
- Hi Andy.
- Hello.
- I have a bit of parish business before we start.
- Oh.
- Yes.
- There is an exciting new fan site created
by a fish listener, fish listener, fish listener.
He's called Luke Delaney.
He has built a website.
It's about fish.
It's called place2no.com.
Place like the fish.
- That's very clever.
- It's very clever.
- We should get him on section naming.
- No, I will not have anyone.
(laughing)
That's mine.
Place2no, it's amazing.
It's basically a huge map of the world
and it contains all the places that we've mentioned
on fish over the last 12 years.
- Wow.
- And if you zoom in on anywhere, it shows you the place
and then you click on it
and it shows you what we've said about that place.
It's amazing.
- It is amazing.
- And there are all sorts of little bells and whistles.
Yeah, yeah.
And I've shown you guys.
- So if you zoom on to Loch Ness,
there's like 500 different megs.
- Exactly.
- Yeah, exactly that.
Anyway, it's so good.
So anyone listening to this,
if you want to check it out,
Luke Delaney has built it.
Thank you so much to you Luke.
And it is place2no.com.
That's place with an eye like the fish.
- Very good.
- Clever.
- Have some facts.
- Got one coming from North Carolina
from someone called Hunter.
- Weird name.
- Oh, 'cause it's also yours.
- Yeah.
- Of course.
Well, he's found an interesting story.
He said, have we come across Joseph Palmer
and Massachusetts man,
eight who in 1830, his beard was hated so much
by local townsfolk that they attempted to shave it off?
So there's a difference,
'cause of course you still can't grow a beard, can you?
- That's very funny.
- And also it's an interesting story.
(laughing)
- Wow.
- One, two.
- The rich start.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Isn't that the grander on tomorrow?
Anyway, so these locals hated his beard.
They attacked this guy.
They tried to shave it off.
And he refused to have it shaved off.
And this is a time when I think beards were banned.
So he refused to bow to social convention.
Apparently he was part of the transcendentalist movement
of New England.
I don't know if that's related to his beard keeping.
I've vaguely been interested in transcendentalism
in my past.
And I didn't know that you had to grow a beard for it.
- Oh, so why did you grow yours?
(laughing)
- It was a mistake.
- This was quite like the only person
who's got a beard as James.
- I have like a go-to beard
'cause that's literally all I can grow.
- Would you keep the beard
even if they banned them on pain of prison?
- No, I wouldn't.
And in actual fact, I feel like even if just the two of you
were strong-willed enough to want to shave it off,
I would be hard pressed to stop you.
(laughing)
- Okay. - Challenge accepted.
- Great.
I just think that like one or two people
can overpower one person and an entire village
can almost certainly overpower one person,
even a bearded person.
- Yeah, you're right.
- It's easier to chop someone's beard off
than it is to give them a good close shave though.
'Cause your beard is close enough to your face
that I would not want to be wrestling with the razor
for fear of doing you any injury,
which I wouldn't want that.
I don't want that.
I just want the beard off in the scenario.
- And actually, almost all beard are close to faces.
So it is sometimes--
- Eventually they--
- It'll be difficult.
- Eventually they are.
You can do a good chop of the main thing.
- You could do a trim.
Yeah, hack it with the pair of garden shears
from a distance as a Santa Claus gig.
- But this guy sounds like he had one of those
amazing 15 foot long bids.
- He did.
And in fact, he's got a tombstone that shows his head
and it is a massively bigger than Santa Claus
as I had a look.
And his tombstone just reads persecuted for wearing a beard.
- Wow.
- Yeah, he's really tense to it.
Anyway, great fact Hunter.
- Great fact.
- That's really good.
- Yeah.
- Here is one from Dre, Falserano.
And they talk about a place in America as well
in Vermont.
And they say they're in Vermont in order to stock trout
in the highest stocked pond in the state.
They transport them via ski lifts.
- Brilliant.
- Cool.
- Isn't that amazing?
- What a weird sight that would be if you were just going out
to do the red run at the top.
And you're in a lift with a bunch of trout.
- That's what I thought.
- Right.
- In your head when I tell you that fact,
what kind of ski lift is it?
- An old-school ski lift where you sit in it
and you pull down the bar and then it takes you
to be like a de-clacketing up, is that it?
- I think you're trying to be funny here Addy.
No, I think you are being funny.
No, no, I'm not.
- Oh, I thought you were trying to be funny.
- Because obviously the most logical thing is to put the barrel
inside one of those big enclosed glass.
- No.
- This is where we come in to a problem,
which is that I am a man of the people
and I've never been skiing.
Whereas you two hoysie toy types.
You know all about the different kinds of ski lift
'cause you're always on the slopes.
- Well, it's just the thing is like,
normally I'd go horse riding
but I'm mostly too cold in the winter.
So I have to go skiing.
- What's the truth?
The trout got upon a lift?
- No, in actual fact, the trout go in a chair lift, it seems.
- Yes.
- What?
- Because I read a newspaper article about this
and it said you may have seen snakes on a plane
but have you ever seen fish on a chair lift?
- No.
- In a box.
- They put buckets and each bucket's got about 400 tiny
trout in it and they put it next to someone
presumably in a chair lift 'cause it will be mad
as they do not put it so.
(laughing)
- Oh, they dismount.
It put skis on the bottom.
- Yeah, exactly.
- Well, it's always had to dismount from a--
- It is.
- Is a ski lift, yeah, it is.
- Oh, I don't know this you see.
Can I tell you a ski lift story?
I've got a secondhand ski lift story.
- Okay.
- My friend Joe, I won't say a certain name
but you both met him.
- Yeah.
- Has been skiing and it was his first time skiing
and after he got to the top for his first run down,
his girlfriend asked him,
"You all right, how do you find the lift?"
And he said, "Yeah, it was okay.
Bit scary, that lift though, isn't it?"
And he had forgotten to put the bar down
with two safes in the lift.
And he had just been hovering over the abyss
for the whole journey up.
- That's really horrifying.
- He also got to the bottom of his first run
and he forgot to put his goggles on.
So his eyes were incredibly red.
- That's all right.
- This article that I read about snakes on a plane
that slash fish on a chair lift
gives an extra bit of information
and it is that Brook Trout,
which is this species of trout,
are notorious for having a fear of heights.
So the more we can do to keep them happy,
the better chance they'll have of having a new home
at the top.
- I'm sorry.
- I'm calling it bullshit.
Notorious is doing a lot of very heavy lifting.
- Notorious.
How can you tell if a fish has a fear of heights?
- Yeah, it's hard.
- Is it high if you're closer to the surface?
- I don't know.
I just think that's such a funny line.
- Incredible.
- It appears to be said quite seriously, so.
- You do get flying trout, don't you?
Isn't that kind of fish?
Or is it a different kind of fish?
- Do they have a fear of flying though?
- Maybe they may be some flying trout
on notorious for having a fear of flying.
- I just imagine one of them being sort of pulled out
of the water in a net,
and they're going, "Wah!"
(laughing)
- Absolutely crazy, brilliant fact, right?
- Great fact.
Just keeping the theme,
I have a fact about a thing in America and evolving ice.
So this comes in from Mark Saltvite.
Here's the question.
Before the invention of planes,
what was the fastest vehicle on earth?
- Well, you have given a bit of a hint, haven't you?
- I have, I shouldn't have done that, but I have now.
- It's you can't take it back.
- I know.
- It's something to do with ice erections.
- Might be.
- You know what I would have said before?
I somehow got the idea that it might be something to do with ice.
- Yeah.
- Like, do you remember they used to have those sort of log flumes,
but they were literal log flumes.
That's in your logger and you cut down a tree
and you put it in a flume,
and people used to sit on those to get home,
and they used to go really fast.
- I thought they were slow log flicks,
but I guess they're a fast ones.
- That's what I mean, yeah.
- Well, that's a good contender.
So Mark says that the answer is the ice yacht.
- Oh, I have.
- And I have never even heard of these things before.
Basically, it's a boat on ice skates with a sail.
- Awesome.
- So the lake, or whatever, is frozen over, or the bay,
and you go whizzing over it on your boat on skates.
- That's clever.
- And Franklin Delano Roosevelt,
president, was an avid ice yachter,
as was his cousin, Ellen Roosevelt.
And sadly, the century, of course,
a lot less ice than these to be,
that there are no ice yachts left.
- Ice yachting, and tragically dying.
- That's cool. - Yeah.
- That's interesting.
- I know, but it's so cool.
- There are plenty of places that have ice.
- There's no reason why they couldn't do it
in Finland, for instance.
- Yeah, that'd be good.
- Yeah.
- If I have to get to Finland for most people, isn't it?
- Not for Finns, no, they could keep doing it, sure.
Maybe they are.
- And Mark has let me know that there is a Hudson River
ice yacht preservation society,
and I think membership is $16 for a year.
- Okay. - It's a bargain.
- Go on, Andy. - I will.
- I'm going to. - Go to your badge.
- I'll get it. - Cool.
- I think listeners to this podcast must think
that we're all absolutely rolling in money,
the amount of money that Dan spends on eBay,
and you spend on these kind of societies.
Will I save all the money on skiing all of a day?
We've got to go somewhere.
(laughing)
- That's amazing.
It reminds me of those ice truckers
that you get in the Baltics, don't you, where?
It's illegal, I think, for them to wear seat belts.
Or something, like because they're driving over ice roads.
But at any stage, the road might just disappear
and they go underwater, so you can't wear the seat belts.
You have to be able to get away, so it's very cool.
- Yeah, that's very cool.
- It reminds me of the beginning to Frankenstein,
which I only recently read, and it's so confusing.
Have you guys read Frankenstein?
- Yeah, I have, yeah.
- Don't you find the beginning incredibly weird,
'cause you know it's about, you know,
Frankenstein is monster.
And then it starts in the Arctic Circle,
watching someone gallop along on an ice carriage,
or carriage on ice skates.
And you think for the first 30 pages,
is it like reading the wrong book?
Anyway, yes, maybe that must have been a thing.
- Yeah.
- Ice carriages, what fun.
Okay, I've got another fact here from Renee Westernhausen.
And this is about left-handedness.
I love this, 'cause Renee's done such a deep dive
into the British newspaper archive,
and has found out that left-handers were barred
from all these professions.
And specifically, opens by saying
you weren't allowed to be a hairdresser.
So they found out that the Ministry of Labor
barred left-handed people from training his hairdressers
until the end of the 1960s.
There's an article, it's mad.
- I think a social chain.
- It makes perfect sense.
- Why?
- Because your hairdresser is standing behind you
on your left-hand side, 'cause they're cutting.
And there's another person sat to your left as well.
And their left-handed hairdresser will be stood
on their right, and the two hairdressers
will be banging arms all the time.
But your hairdresser doesn't stay on one side of you
for the whole hair cut.
But those, they do, yeah.
- And explains a lot.
- Just another short back and left, please.
- Yeah, great, yeah, yeah.
- We didn't mention the beard as actually on one side.
- And so I could look in the mirror
and keep telling my head to pretend that I'm talking
to someone else.
- And you dressed half of you like a lady,
as well, haven't you?
- You're a vulnerable show.
- Yeah.
- It's nice, it just gets you a bit of company, doesn't it?
- It's guaranteed, isn't it?
- Yeah.
- A bit of an intelligent conversation for a change.
- I think that there would be bumping into each other,
you're right.
But is it that they couldn't make the scissors for them?
The left-handed scissors.
- I see.
- Or any right-handed barber scissors?
- It was just that people were generally suspicious.
And I did look into the archive as well.
And I don't think it was outright banned.
And there was a lot of complaints
about prejudice in other industries
against left-handed people.
But sometimes, you know,
plasterers, carpenter's, tile fixers.
- Agreed.
- All of those.
- Sheet metal workers.
- Definitely are my guide.
- Do you imagine having sheet metal in your house
made by a left-handed?
- Oh god, it wouldn't.
- The wrong way around.
- You wouldn't be able to put it on the better tool, would you?
(laughing)
So they go, oh my god.
And then I found this amazing thing
when I was diving into the British newspaper archive,
looking for this.
And I just found the headline from 1930.
Husband who in 20 years had never seen his wife's left hand,
which was an incredible story.
- Charles Gelliatz, husband.
(laughing)
- It's too big of a chance here when you're too close to it.
- It was a story about this guy who'd married someone
who always wore a hand bandage.
And he'd been too polite to ask her,
is that what's up with your hand?
And then eventually she died of sepsis in her late 40s.
And so the doctors came down and said,
"Golly, why is your wife's hand bandage?"
And he said, "I don't know, I never really asked."
- Yeah.
- And he took the bandage off
and all that thing was it fallen off.
Oh.
- That had such a sad ending.
- You sold it as such a funny story
that I ended up being.
- Do you know what my husband says?
I have a problem with this.
I always start really sad stories
with a really perky tone.
- Yes, that's true.
- It was bad, wasn't it?
- Certainly in this case, that's what happened, yeah.
- Yeah, I'm sorry about that.
Oh well.
(laughing)
Anyway, James, anything, anything?
- Cheers up.
- Can I tell you about the Raspberry Crazy Ant?
- Yes.
- 'Cause Brian has told me about it.
It's a serious pest along the Gulf Coast of America,
but it's drawn to electronic devices
and electrical systems.
Brian had an infestation on his personal laptop.
And it's called the Raspberry Crazy Ant.
Crazy, obviously, because it runs around
in a crazy manner.
Raspberry, because they were named after the exterminator
who reported them Tom Raspberry.
(laughing)
- Excellent.
- Having read the original email
and thought that was good for you, James.
I had misremembered it and thought you were going to say
they only go for Raspberry Pi.
There's little computers.
- Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no.
- I made laptop ones, but it's named off the Tom Raspberry.
- Go to Tom Raspberry.
Now it just looks into them and found
that actually NASA has big problems with these ants.
- Really?
- Because the ants keep going into the control station.
- Oh no.
- And Tom Raspberry actually was hired by NASA
to sort out the Raspberry Crazy Ant.
- Incredible.
- Wow.
- Maybe they're trying to take over the space program.
- Maybe they're trying to get to the moon.
- That's so, obviously, what they're trying to do.
They're organized.
They don't need much air.
I'm guessing.
(laughing)
- They should go to the rocket rather than the control
center if they want to get to the moon, shouldn't they?
- That's a good point, actually.
- Maybe they've got...
- Unless another lot of ants went into the rocket
and these guys are direct in the...
- No doubt, they've got colleagues in the rocket.
- Yeah.
- I don't know if they need a rocket,
because I've got a children's book at home
about what Anor can put a star back in the sky.
And it turns out to be ants because they all are so good
at teamwork that they climb on top of each other
and the top one can get to the moon.
- It's just that started off with quite a nice children's story.
What did they all get by all today?
(laughing)
Some of our biolimaltrums have been...
- Here's one from Rodrigo Pimentel.
- What great name.
- I'm just gonna read the thing to you, right?
As you probably well know,
the oldest works of what we call ancient Greek literature
were Homer's epic poems, the Iliad and the Odyssey,
composed around 650 BC.
The earliest literary prose in Ancient Greece
is widely accepted as being Herodotus' histories
from about 430 BC.
- Okay.
- Now, in episode 55, Anor says that the fire hose
was invented in Ancient Greece
and made out of an ox's intestine, okay?
The few sources I could find date this to around 400 BC.
It seems like for the Ancient Greeks,
it really was narrowly prose before hosts.
(laughing)
- I see, I get it.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
- And Rodrigo does say, "I'm sorry," at the end of it.
- Oh, that was really close.
- That was really close.
- Definitely.
- No way.
- I think that's wonderful.
- An incredibly labored route to a below par upon
is what we live for.
(laughing)
(upbeat music)
- What about a fact here, Jo Hanley?
Here's one from you.
This was brilliant, actually.
So Demetri's Shostakovich, maybe one of the greatest
composers of the 20th century.
- Russian heavy duty.
- Heavy duty, yes.
- Second world war inspired.
- Absolutely, yeah.
Bear that in mind.
- Not a laugh a minute.
Could soundtrack your anecdote, actually.
(laughing)
- All right, let's be careful about anecdote digs.
Okay.
(laughing)
Who soundtracks yours?
- Jokane.
(laughing)
- Shostakovich went to see Jesus Christ superstar
the premier in 1972.
- Really?
- He absolutely loved it.
He said it was so good he wished he'd composed it himself.
- Yes.
- Yeah.
And I, God, I hope Angelo Dweber is listening to this
'cause that's gotta be the best moment of his life.
Or actually, maybe it wouldn't surprise him.
(laughing)
- It's amazing.
Shostakovich wishes he'd written Jesus Christ superstar.
- Well, maybe you come out of it with your feet tapping
in a way that you don't out of,
I can't name any Shostakovich, I'm afraid.
- Come on.
Piano concert on number three.
(laughing)
- Prelude in D.
- Well, that's, I mean, gosh.
I wouldn't even put it in Andrew Lloyd Webber's top five.
- Do you know neither would I.
(laughing)
- That's so funny.
- But maybe Shostakovich never heard
of Joseph and the amazing technical dream come true.
(laughing)
- Okay, here is another one from Lucas, S-H,
or Lucas, Shh.
Lucas says, "Hi everyone, my fact is that Karl Marx
was first cousins with Gerard Phillips,
the founder of the Phillips company of toothbrush fame."
- That's good.
- Is Phillips a famous toothbrush?
- Yeah.
- Oh, I know.
- I think of them as making walkmins.
- If you ever brush your teeth, you wouldn't know.
(laughing)
- I don't feel it.
- You start.
(laughing)
- I don't believe the only company
that makes walkmins is Sony.
(laughing)
- By definition.
- Sorry, you're right.
You're absolutely right.
They're gonna sue me now.
- James, you have just avoided
a crisis level email event in your box.
That was stunning.
I've never been more grateful.
- So this guy, Gerard Phillips,
his paternal grandmother was Sophie Pressberg
and she was a sister of Henriette Pressberg
who was Karl Marx's mother.
- Oh wow.
- Wow.
So actually it might be once removed, perhaps.
- Oh sure.
- But yeah, Marx didn't really get on with his mum
because he was going off spending loads of money
in his student days.
- I think I remember this, didn't she?
She was really pissed off with him about it.
She thought he was a useless.
- Yeah, and also she was worried about him
and she said you must avoid everything
that can make things worse.
You must not get overheated.
You must not drink a lot of wine or coffee
or eat anything pungent or eat pepper or other spices.
You must not spoke any tobacco.
Must not stay up late in the evening
and you must always rise early.
- Wow.
- And basically he just kept asking for money,
asking for money and then they fell out
and then in fact no one in his family went to his wedding.
- A house. - Really?
I don't know whether he would have been hanging out
with the head of the Phillips company
because the family's kind of didn't hang out
together that much.
- It feels unlikely that he would have been hanging out
with big business or they wouldn't have agreed on much.
- No. - But maybe on dental hygiene.
I mean that should be for everyone.
- That was the thing they can agree.
- Family Christmas, stick to teeth.
- Everyone agrees we all want nice teeth.
(laughing)
- And we all deserve nice teeth.
- For the people. - Yes.
- And if you don't have a tooth,
someone else should give their tooth to you.
- Nope, stop, Carl.
(laughing)
- Everyone should have the same number of teeth.
- I got one last one from Doug Steen
from Fort Collins.
Very American, the correspondence today.
I don't plan it.
You'll be staggered here.
But this is about a place called King County
in Washington state.
Who do you think it's named after?
- Martin Luther. - Martin Luther.
- Oh, how interesting.
- It's named for Martin Luther King Jr.
But Martin Luther King Jr. was born 77 years
after it was named King County.
(humming)
- So they were previously named after a guy called George King
who was a gold prospector or something
but then later on they retconned it.
- Bingo, was it?
- Yeah, it was originally named after William Rufus Devan King
who was the vice president briefly and not very well.
And then he died after about 45 days in the job.
And he was a slave owner.
- Oh, well done.
- He was a roller coaster.
(laughing)
- I really took you on the tragic path.
You were saying, you know what, he wasn't a great guy.
So yeah, he was apparently one of the worst vice presidents
of all time.
He never did anything vice presidential.
You know, all those important jobs
that the vice president has to do.
And also another thing, the only other detail I found about him
is that he wore powdered wigs long after they'd gone out
of fashion.
So if you didn't already hate him for owning 500 slaves,
the powdered wigs thing really put the tin lid on there.
So he was King.
It was named King County after him
and then it was renamed after Martin Luther King.
- That's good.
- How brilliant.
What a slap in the face for Rufus.
- Absolutely.
- They could always just name it after another king
in the future, like King Prince Charles.
- Yep.
- Or like Stephen King.
- Oh, that's a good idea.
- It'd be great if you were called like Smith County
and you just changed it every few months.
- That was the most fashionable Smith at the time.
- And what you're saying is that Martin Luther King's reputation
is apparently going to take a massive nose dive
and it'll be necessary to say,
what about Stephen King?
He's a must've never known who's going to get cancelled for you.
(laughing)
- Okay, on that note, I think I have a clue
who's going to get cancelled next James.
(laughing)
We should have some, we should dish out some facts
to our new friends of the podcast.
So if you go to patreon.com/plubfish
and you sign up to Clubfish at the highest tier,
the friend of the podcast tier,
you can get a fact from our archive,
one of our headline facts dedicated to you forever.
You can become its custodian and keep it.
And we're going to dish out a load of those now.
So let's get cracking.
Who has a fact that they would like to give out?
- Okay, I think I've got one.
The first item sold on eBay was a broken laser pointer.
It was bought by a man who collected broken laser pointers.
And that is now under the custodianship of Robert Fink.
- Oh, good question.
- This guy must've thought all of his Christmases
are covered once.
Like he just goes on eBay thinking I wonder what's on here.
And he finds the one thing that he collects.
- He did it.
It was the best day of downshiners life.
(laughing)
So to this day, very good.
- Yeah, that's wonderful.
Great fact.
We're at a fact here for Thomas Welch.
I bestowed this one upon you.
And that is that when Alexander Fleming's neighbors
foiled a burglary at his house as a thank you gift,
he gave them some mold.
- Brilliant.
- But it's Alexander Fleming.
So it's not.
- It's a penicillin mold?
- It was indeed penicillin mold
'cause it's Alexander Fleming.
So it's not just like anyone giving you mold.
- It's a celebrity mold.
- It was celebrity mold, yeah.
And I think.
- That's a format.
- Sorry.
- We've cultured molds from a random body sample
taken from these celebrities
and you've got to match them up.
- And then you turn it into sourdough bread
and you taste the bread and see if you can guess
which celebrity it is.
- Exactly, is this Bradley Walsh?
Is it?
- Bradley Walsh.
(laughing)
- Breadpit.
- Okay, now we're cooking.
Now we're cooking.
- Yeah.
It's about to be the centenary of that.
It was 1928 that he discovered penicillin.
- Wow.
- So be prepared for a lot of.
- Are we gonna have like big sort of street parties
in London where everyone gets a lot of mold?
- Yeah, maybe.
Yeah, I think we should.
- You only get invited if you're a fun guy.
- Completely different.
- Let's have another fact.
This one goes out.
- Ooh.
- Oohie.
- Sorry.
- Let's go on to a fact.
- Let's go on to a fact with a gray crinac or crinac.
Your fact is the earliest known ice cream recipe
suggests flavoring with poo.
(laughing)
- That's what it is.
- Yeah, it's a cheeky, isn't it?
We do cheeky things with our facts.
It's whale poo.
- Oh.
- Does it amber grease?
- Yeah, amber grease.
- It's not that's not cheeky at all.
- No, it's not.
It's still poo.
- It's still poo?
- No, no, no.
- It's in normally vomit.
- That's a good point.
Does it come out of their mouths not the potions?
- I believe it comes out of both,
but I think vomit is more common.
- It might be wrong.
- That's true.
It is also poo.
It amber grease is also poo.
- Sure.
- Yeah, yeah.
- I wanted to pronounce it amber grease, but I feel like.
- I call it amber grease.
- You call it amber grease.
Who knows?
It's not common enough to have too many emails.
- Not to have an argument about.
No, it's fine, it's fine, it's fine.
Anyway, that's a fastpot.
- Okay, very delicious.
I've got another one here.
Another one from the lower regions.
(laughing)
And it goes now to Jake McCann.
Jake, your fact is the dog pee makes street lights collapse.
- I remember this one.
- Yeah, and this is basically dogs
weighing on street lights and then getting more and more
weak because of the urea.
- Yeah.
And the only way to solve it is to weigh on the other side.
- No, I think the way to do it is to not allow dogs
to weigh on lamp posts.
But I mean, it's hard to stop it.
- Man, that's hard to stop, yeah.
- And it does feel like you're gonna know
if it's on the brink of collapse, aren't you?
It's not like one day would have to be a very acidic dog
we are reckon for it to be just a new brand new street lamp.
And it just keels over.
- Yeah, that's free.
- So here's another fact.
And this is the fact that after the button was invented,
it took more than a thousand years
for someone to invent the button hole.
And I am going to give this fact to Sean Tobin Murphy,
a fantastic fact.
- That's a classic fact, so it's a classic fish fact.
- It's really, it's in, there are certain formats
that various packs fit into.
And that's of the format.
It took loads of years before someone to invent
the hole in the basket like the tin was invented
200 years before the tin opener.
- Yes.
- And everyone just had full tins of sweet cod
and didn't know what to do with the most of the fish.
- Yeah.
(laughing)
- So many completely avoidable famines.
- It's terrible.
- Stop it, I get a tens.
(laughing)
- But yeah, like with the buttons,
it's like they had a loop of cotton
or something that you put the button in.
Like a duffel coat.
- Right, like a cool design feature.
- Yeah.
- And also a button hole is a specific,
you know, it has to be strengthened
around the hole, right?
It's not just a hole,
it's not just a slit.
- You can't just cut it.
Yeah, a little known fact.
- Yeah, yeah.
- That's why I've been going wrong.
So I'll go close the regs.
(laughing)
Insert a button hole everywhere here.
- Should we have another?
- Yeah.
- This one goes out to Tom Dicks
and the fact is, as a baby,
St. Nicholas refused to drink his mother's breast milk
on fast days.
(laughing)
His holiness.
So good.
- Love this fact.
- He'd be, I mean, it's really dangerous
for a newborn baby to go a whole day without breast milk.
- Yep.
- It's really silly.
- It was on Wednesdays and Fridays.
- Twice or two days a week.
- I think he did it in the evening
he allowed himself to break his fast.
- Did he?
- I presume that was absolutely ravidous.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Also her breast by the end of the day
will be very turgid, very uncomfortable for the mother.
- Right.
- It doesn't sound like it's good for anyone, really.
But that's fasting, you know,
you've got to show too many cheeks
like a lot of people are fasting.
- What, I have a, like a-
- It's just a little suck on the food.
(laughing)
- When his mom is not like it.
- Definitely.
(laughing)
- It's like Father Christmas ain't Nicholas.
- How many, how many St. Nicholas's are there?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- I'm just imagining Father Christmas
saw he on his mother's face.
- I don't think he had a beard in my stays.
(laughing)
- That would be very uncomfortable.
- God.
- When was he around?
- What St. Nicholas, I don't know,
third-ish century or fourth or something.
- Okay, so what I'm asking is did the Ho Ho Ho's come before prose
or before prose?
- That's it.
- That's right.
St. Nicholas was born in 270 AD.
Okay, so we go prose, hose, Ho Ho Ho's.
- Now we're cooking.
- That's right.
- Got it. - Lovely.
- Lovely.
- Now he established that.
(laughing)
- Okay, here's my last one for the day
and this now goes under the custodian ship
of Zarco Naritz and Zarco,
your headline fact is when Ronald Reagan left office,
he left a note on the White House lawn for the squirrels,
warning them to beware of George Bush's dogs.
- It's so sweet.
- President. - If he wanted him.
- Presidential handovers were nice
to back in the day, weren't they?
Then I'm gonna have you locked up.
No, I'm gonna have you locked up.
Well, I pardon myself, eat it.
(laughing)
- Okay, one more.
- One more and here is one for Beth.
Just Beth.
And this Beth is that Las Vegas hosts an awards ceremony
for people who make awards.
- Love it.
- So good.
- Fantastic.
- Of course, 'cause there's an awards ceremony
for everything, isn't there?
- Yeah, yeah.
And we said at the time there were different categories.
There's best trophy and best plaque.
- Yeah, really good.
What list of celebrity do you think you'd have to be
to be asked to make the after-dinner speech
of that awards ceremony?
- I don't think you're gonna get it, Anna.
- I'm sorry.
(laughing)
I'm really sorry.
I think maybe a bit of profile raising
and you could get there, but I think you need it.
(laughing)
Oh, right, well look, that's it.
That's another episode of Little Fish.
- So soon.
If you have a fact for us
that you'd like us to read out on the show,
just email it to podcast@qy.com.
We read every single one.
They're all brilliant.
They're so much fun to read.
I made my point.
- Are they all brilliant?
- No, they're not all brilliant.
But your fact will be.
So send it to podcast@qy.com.
No, it's so wonderful hearing from everyone.
If you've got something for Drop as a Lion
or audience feedback show,
it's the same email address podcast@qy.com.
So we'll see you there
and we'll see you again in a few days
for another episode of No Such Thing as a Fish.
Bye for now.
(upbeat music)